Where the embeddings are fast becoming the de facto choice for representing words,
词嵌入快速成为人们实际选择的词表示法
especially for use and deep neural networks.
主要用于深度神经网络
But why do these techniques work so well?
但是 为什么这些技术的效果这么好？
Doesn't it seem almost magical that you can actually do arithmetic with words,
你可以对词进行算术运算
like woman minus man plus king equals queen?
例如 woman - man + king = queen , 这难道不神奇吗？
The answer might lie in the distributional hypothesis,
关键在于分布假设
which states that words that occur in the same contexts tend to have similar meanings.
根据分布假设 同一上下文中出现的词有相似含义
For example, consider this sentence.
例如这个句子
Would you like to have a cup of blank?
“你想来杯&lt;u&gt;     &lt;/u&gt;吗？”
Okay. How about, I like my blank black.
那么 这个句子呢 “我想要杯黑&lt;u&gt;     ”&lt;/u&gt;
One more, I need my morning blank before I can do anything.
还有一个句子 “早上我想先喝&lt;u&gt;      &lt;/u&gt; 再做其它事情”
What are you thinking?
你认为是什么？
Tea? Coffee? What give you the hint?
“茶”？ “咖啡”？ 是哪个词给了你提示？
Cup? Black? Morning? But it could be either of the two, right?
“杯”？ “黑”？ “早上”？ 两个都有可能 对吧？
And that's the point.
这就是关键所在
In these contexts, tea and coffee are actually similar.
在这些上下文中 “茶”和“咖啡”实际是相似的
Therefore, when a large collection of sentences is used to learn in embedding,
因此 使用大量句子训练嵌入模型时
words with common context words tend to get pulled closer and closer together.
拥有相同上下文的词汇被拉得越来越近
Of course, there could also be contexts in which tea and coffee are dissimilar.
当然 在一些上下文中 “茶”和“咖啡”是有差异的
For example, blank grounds are great for composting.
例如 “&lt;u&gt;     &lt;/u&gt;渣非常适合做堆肥”
Or, I prefer loose leaf blank.
或者 “我喜欢喝散叶&lt;u&gt;     &lt;/u&gt;”
Here we are clearly talking about coffee grounds,
很明显 我们在这里说的是“咖啡渣”
and loose leaf tea.
和“散叶茶”
How do we capture these similarities and differences in the same embedding?
如何在同一次嵌入中捕捉这些相似性和差异性？
By adding another dimension.
方法就是增加另一个维度
Let's see how.
我们看一下如何增加维度
Words can be close along one dimension.
在一个维度上 词可能互相接近
Here, tea and coffee are both beverages,
这里 “茶”和“咖啡”都是饮料
but separated along some other dimension.
但在另一个维度上 可能互相远离
Maybe this dimension captures all the variability among beverages.
可能这个维度包含了各种饮料之间的所有差异性
In a human language,
在自然语言中
there are many more dimensions along which word meanings can vary.
还有很多维度 在这些维度上 词的含义各不相同
And the more dimensions you can capture in your word vector,
词向量中捕捉的维度越多
the more expressive that representation will be.
表示法的表达越充分
But how many dimensions do you really need?
但是 到底需要多少个维度呢？
Consider a typical neural network architecture
想象用于 NLP 任务 例如词预测的
designed for an NLP task, say word prediction.
一个典型神经网络架构
It's common to use a word embedding layer that
我们常见的是使用一个词嵌入层
produces a vector with a few hundred dimensions,
生成具有几百个维度的向量
but that's significantly small compared to using one heart encodings directly,
但与直接使用独热编码相比 这个数量小得多
which are as large as the size of the vocabulary,
独热编码有时可以达到
sometimes in tens of thousands of words.
几万个词的词汇表的大小
Also, if you learn the embedding as part of the model training process,
另外 如果你在模型训练过程中训练词嵌入
you can obtain a representation that captures
你会学习到一种表示法
the dimensions that are most relevant for your task.
其捕捉了与你任务的相关性最强的维度
This often adds complexity.
这通常会增加复杂度
So unless you're building a model for
因此 除非你构建的是
a very narrow application like one that deals with medical terminology,
适用范围非常小的模型 例如 处理医疗术语的模型
you can use a pre-trained embedding as a look-up.
可以使用预训练的词嵌入模型进行查找
For example, work to veck or glove.
例如 Word2vec 或 GloVe
Then you only need to train the layer specific to your task.
然后你只需要训练与任务相关的特定层
Compare this with the network architecture for a computer vision task, say,
将其与用于计算机视觉 例如 图像分类的任务的网络架构相比较
image classification, the raw input here is also very high dimensional.
这里的原始输入也是高维度的
For example, even 128 by 128 Image contains over 16 thousand pixels.
例如 即使一张 128*128 的图像 也包含 16000 多个像素
We typically use convolutional layers to exploit
我们一般使用卷积层
the spatial relationships and image data and reduce this dimensionality.
探索图像数据中的空间关系 减少维数
Early stages and visual processing are often transferable across tasks,
早期的视觉处理技术可以应用在不同的任务中
so it is common to use some pre-trained layers from an existing network,
因此通常使用现有网络中的某些预训练层
like Alex nad or BTG 16 and only learn the later layers.
例如 Alex nad 或 BTG 16 只学习后面的层
Come to think of it, using an embedding look up for NLP
想想看 使用词嵌入查找进行 NLP
is not on like using pre-treated layers for computer vision.
与计算机视觉使用预处理层没有什么不同
Both are great examples of transfer learning.
两者都是很好的迁移学习的例子